<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dashboard on Documentation for Umuzi Tech Department</title>
    <link>/tech-department/tags/dashboard/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Dashboard on Documentation for Umuzi Tech Department</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/tech-department/tags/dashboard/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Live Dashboard Assignment</title>
      <link>/tech-department/projects/data-science-specific/dashboards/live_dashboards/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tech-department/projects/data-science-specific/dashboards/live_dashboards/</guid>
      <description>Watch the sessions on Dashboarding with Notebooks to help you create a dashboard with Jupyter Notebooks and Plotly.
Write a script that will get the latest figures data from ReliefWeb&amp;rsquo;s Crisis Figures on a daily basis. The Latest Figures dataset contains information on the world&amp;rsquo;s most pressing humanitarian crises. The data, curated by ReliefWeb&amp;rsquo;s editorial team based on its relevance to the humanitarian community, is updated daily.
Create interactive graphs showing the number of People in Need and People Targeted for Assistance by country.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Webscraping and Live Dashboard Assignment</title>
      <link>/tech-department/projects/data-science-specific/dashboards/webscraping_plus_dashboards/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tech-department/projects/data-science-specific/dashboards/webscraping_plus_dashboards/</guid>
      <description>Assignment Use beautifulsoup and regular expressions (regex) to scrape the data of provincial dam levels from the Department of Water and Sanitation.
Create a dashboard with graphs showing the current and previous week&amp;rsquo;s dam levels by province, and compare it to the water levels from the previous year. Your dashboard should update weekly (in other words, you can&amp;rsquo;t just copy and paste this week&amp;rsquo;s data to your notebook).
Think about  What type of graph will show this information best?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>