<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Documentation for Umuzi Tech Department</title>
    <link>/4-projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Documentation for Umuzi Tech Department</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2016 16:50:16 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/4-projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Build your first personal website</title>
      <link>/4-projects/first-personal-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2019 16:50:16 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/4-projects/first-personal-website/</guid>
      <description>For the learnership you will create a website with your CV and a portfolio of your work. Create the website and host it on Github. You will be updating your portfolio throughout the learnership.
Brief: Create a Personal Website
Summary: Create a personal website to showcase your talents and ambitions and to let the world know more about you. In the future, this will be the website you send to potential employers, so it should have the ability to show a portfolio of your best work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Development of a Portfolio website</title>
      <link>/4-projects/development-of-a-portfolio-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2019 16:50:16 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/4-projects/development-of-a-portfolio-website/</guid>
      <description>with HTML5, CSS and bootstrap
TODO</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Expose a simple REST api for your game</title>
      <link>/4-projects/expose-a-simple-rest-api-for-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2019 16:50:16 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/4-projects/expose-a-simple-rest-api-for-game/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to submit your project</title>
      <link>/4-projects/how-to-submit-your-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2019 16:50:16 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/4-projects/how-to-submit-your-project/</guid>
      <description>How to submit your project Create a repo on github. The repo name should be: &amp;ldquo;umuzi-project-[the project description filename without the extension]&amp;ldquo;. Eg: if you are completing the project described in &amp;ldquo;basic-website-frontend-events.md&amp;rdquo; then you should name your github repo: &amp;ldquo;umuzi-project-basic-website-frontend-events&amp;rdquo;
All coding projects will be submitted as git repos. You are expected to use git properly, you will be penalised if you only have one gigantic commit or if your commit messages are nonesense.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OOP in Js</title>
      <link>/4-projects/oop-in-js/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2019 16:50:16 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/4-projects/oop-in-js/</guid>
      <description>Assignment 1: Basics Assignment Description
Create a class called Person which defines the generic data and functionality of a person. Now as we know there are a lot of things involved with a Person e.g (age,gender,their address, height, shoe size, passport number, etc). but in this case we are only interested in showing their name, age, gender, and interests, and we also want to be able to write a short introduction about them based on this data, and get them to say Hello.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>