<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Git on Documentation for Umuzi Tech Department</title>
    <link>/tech-department/tags/git/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Git on Documentation for Umuzi Tech Department</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/tech-department/tags/git/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Git Basic Exercises</title>
      <link>/tech-department/projects/git-exercises/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tech-department/projects/git-exercises/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This little exercise will take you through the basic git mechanisms you need to know about in order to be productive. By the end of this exercise you&amp;rsquo;ll be able to create and manage your own git repos.
IMPORTANT Make sure you go through the prerequisites listed above. Otherwise you&amp;rsquo;ll be clueless!
Skillz you&amp;rsquo;ll learn By the end of this you are expected to know:
 How to set up a repository on Github How to make commits How to make branches and switch between them How to use gitignore files How to merge branches How to overcome merge conflicts  When you are finished with these excercises come re-read this section and make sure you know what all these things mean.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Version Control</title>
      <link>/tech-department/topics/ncit/115362/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tech-department/topics/ncit/115362/</guid>
      <description>1. Libraries and organising projects Working with libraries In your life as a coder, you will use external libraries to help make your software development easier and faster. A JavaScript library is pre-written JavaScript code (functions, objects, definitions) which allows for easier development of JavaScript-based applications and websites. If you haven’t discovered already, there are thousands of libraries available for you to use and the developers of these libraries are updating them all the time.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>